https://www.sco.org.uk/privacy-and-cookie-policy

Skip to main contentSite Menu.
Support Us
DonateSCO Patrons250 SocietyLegaciesBusiness PartnershipsTrusts and FoundationsAmerican Support
About Us
Latest NewsWho's WhoShopSubscriptionsCareers and AuditionsPressContact UsYoutubeFacebookTwitterInstagramLinkedinReturn to mainThis page sets out the details of Scottish Chamber Orchestra's privacy and cookie policy in relation to information collected about you. WHO WE AREScottish Chamber Orchestra4 Royal TerraceEdinburgh EH7 5ABWe are registered as a Scottish Charity, and our registration number is: SC015039We are registered as a data controller under the Data Protection Act 1998, and our Data Protection Register number is: Z6488096. Any electronic communications will be made in accordance with the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (PECR). WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?We collect the personal data that you may volunteer as part of ticket bookings, subscriptions, online purchases, donation forms, newsletter sign-ups, audience surveys, membership forms and participation feedback forms.Personal information we collect may include:Your name, title, gender and date of birth;Postal address, email address and phone number;Family and spouse/partner details, and relationships to other donors;Current interests and activities.Ticket purchase and event registration / attendance;Online retail purchases;Contact preferences;Musical ability, including any relevant qualifications;Gift information, including Direct Debit bank details where applicable;Gift Aid status;Details of correspondence sent to you, or received from you;Donor status and wealth assessment information;Employment information and professional activities;Where relevant, selected media coverage;Any other information provided by yourself at the request of Scottish Chamber Orchestra.Information we have sent you regarding events, services or products related to Scottish Chamber Orchestra such as concerts, workshops, talks, classes, trips, recordings, or offers.Information on our fundraising operations, including occasional requests to consider giving financial support to Scottish Chamber Orchestra, or to ask you to consider supporting us in other ways.Other relevant communications based upon your relationship with Scottish Chamber Orchestra.When we ask you to provide your personal information we will let you know why we are asking and how we will use your data, by directing you towards this notice. WHAT WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATIONDepending on your relationship with Scottish Chamber Orchestra, and the preferences you have indicated, data we hold may be used by us for the following purposes: To send you promotional, marketing or fundraising information by post, telephone or electronic means. These types of communications can include and involve:Data screening and cleansing, to check if we have accurate contact details for you - see How We Update, Screen and Analyse your Information for further details.Wealth screening and research, to help us understand our subscribers, donors, ticket buyers and potential donors, including gathering information from publicly available resources to give an insight into your philanthropic interests and ability to support Scottish Chamber Orchestra. See How we update, screen and analyse your information for further information.To send you surveys, and for market research purposes.To manage any memberships you may have with the SCO, this includes membership to the SCO Chorus, 250 Society and Patron scheme.Tools which may be used to monitor the effectiveness of our communications with you include: email tracking which records when an e-newsletter from us is opened and/or how many links are clicked within the message. The data from this tracking is generally used in an aggregated and anonymised form.You can opt out of any / all of our communications at any point simply by contacting us. There are some membership, subscription, ticket buyer and donation communications that we are required to send you regardless of your contact preferences. These are essential communications deemed necessary to fulfil our contractual obligations to you. These include Direct Debit confirmations and advanced notices, thank you letters, communications informing you of changes or cancellations to concerts and events you have booked for, subscription benefits such as SCO News magazine, renewal reminders, Gift Aid confirmation letters and querying returned mail or bounced Direct Debit payments with you. HOW WE UPDATE, SCREEN AND ANALYSE YOUR INFORMATIONWe continuously review records of supporters to ensure your data is as accurate as possible. We may consult alternative sources in order undertake these checks such as:Royal Mail National Change of Address database (NCOA);BT Operator Services Information System (OSIS);Reviewing employment information that you have made publicly available via social media;Newspaper articles, publications and company websites;Companies House and other company information databases;Charity Commission and Office of the Scottish Charity Regulator (OSCR) registers;Any other publicly available sources.Where we appoint an external party to undertake a screening of information, any such arrangements will be subject to a formal agreement between Scottish Chamber Orchestra and that organisation, to protect the security of your data.We may segment the information we hold about you in our database based on a proprietary score. These scores are calculated using personal data, as well as how engaged with us you have previously been and indicators of future engagement. Analysis of this helps us understand our members, subscribers, ticket buyers, donors and potential donors to ensure we are efficient and that only relevant communications are sent to you.You can opt-out of your data being utilised for wealth screening, data cleaning or analysis (with the aims of targeting communications with you appropriately, or finding up to date contact information in the case of gone away mail) simply by contacting us.WHERE YOUR INFORMATION MIGHT BE SHAREDWe only disclose personal data with other data controllers where there is a legitimate business reason for doing so or with data processors carrying out work on our behalf. Legitimate business reasons would include sharing personal data with other data controllers where we or they are selling or distributing tickets on each other’s behalf and /or we are joint partners in a project, concert or subscription series. DATA CONTROLLERSThis is the list of Data Controllers that we share personal data with, but only in relation to the particular event, project or subscription with which your personal data would be connected.The Queen’s HallThe Usher HallEdinburgh International FestivalGlasgow LifeThe Byre TheatreUniversity of St AndrewsMidsteeple Box OfficeAberdeen Performing ArtsHorsecross Arts, PerthUniversity of YorkBBC Scottish Symphony OrchestraRoyal Scottish National OrchestraRoyal Conservatoire of ScotlandSt Mary's Music SchoolWe also employ companies to act as approved data processors for Scottish Chamber Orchestra, and we retain full responsibility for your personal data. Data processors will act only on our instructions. OUR DATA PROCESSORS Purple Seven - data management & communication system Vital Statistics linked with relevant Box Offices and venues pertaining to your bookingSmartDebit – online direct debit collection toolSagepay – online credit and debit card payment serviceBlackbaud - hosted Customer Relationship Management systemsDimensions - mailing houses for the sending of our SCO News magazine, season brochures and targeted marketing campaignsPinpoint Scotland – mailing house used to send direct mail to previous attendersHotjar - behaviour analytics and user feedback service that helps the SCO understand the behaviour of website users and get their feedback through tools such as heatmaps, session recordings, and surveysMailchimp - bulk email distribution servicesSurvey Monkey - Online Survey toolLexusNexus - data cleaning and enrichmentEventBrite – online event booking toolGroupanizer – online group organisation toolBaker Richards Consulting Ltd. - Data AnalystsSpektrix - hosted ticketing and customer service management systemDotdigital - bulk email distribution servicesSupercool - website developersWe may occasionally need to transfer your personal information overseas, for instance to bulk email distributor, MailChimp or online survey tools, Survey Monkey. Where this is necessary, this may be to countries or territories around the world. We are required to ensure any transfers of data will be done securely, in accordance with best practice, and in compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998.Your data will never be sold or passed to any third party for any other purpose. HOW WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SECURE?We have implemented security procedures, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:unauthorised access;improper use or disclosure;unauthorised modification.All our employees and data processors, who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data are legally obliged to respect the confidentiality of our supporters’ personal data. HOW CAN I ACCESS AND CORRECT THE INFORMATION HELD ABOUT ME?You can ask us if we are keeping any personal data about you and you can also request to receive a copy of that personal data – this is called a Subject Access Request.To make a Subject Access Request you will need to provide adequate proof of identity such as a copy of your passport, birth certificate or driving licence before your request can be processed.Please try to be as clear as possible about the information you are seeking.Once we have received your Subject Access Request, and proof of identity, you will receive a response from us within 40 days and you will be able to get copies of any information we hold on you. However, exemptions to disclosure may apply in some circumstances.Subject Access Requests should be sent to:Finance DirectorScottish Chamber Orchestra4 Royal TerraceEdinburghEH7 5ABOr by email by contacting us.At any time you may request that we delete or correct your personal information. If you wish to correct any information on you held by Scottish Chamber Orchestra, simply contact us.COOKIESThis website uses cookies. By using this website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to the Scottish Chamber Orchestra use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.There are two main kinds of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are deleted from your computer when you close your browser, whereas persistent cookies remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach their expiry date.These cookies are placed in the browser file of your computer or device in order that we can monitor the number of visitors accessing the website and their journeys through and dwell time there, so we can improve the services we offer and the layout and functionality of the site. The delivery of cookies will enable us to ensure you are receiving the best service possible while accessing our website. You can delete these cookies from your computer, however if you do so you may find that you are not able to receive the best user experience whilst on this website.Scottish Chamber Orchestra uses Google Analytics to analyse the use of this website. Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of the website. Google will store and use this information.Google's privacy policy is available at: www.google.com/policies/privac...Refusing CookiesMost browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies.Managing cookiesIt is easy to manage your cookies by adjusting your browser settings. For more information about cookies and how to opt-out, visit any of the following industry bodies:www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.orgEuropean interactive digital advertising alliance – http://www.youronlinechoicesDigital Advertising Alliance – http://www.youronlinechoices.c...Network Advertising Initiative – http://www.networkadvertising....BrowsersAll browsers are different, but by adjusting your browser settings you can prevent your browsing from being tracked. Here are links to the help pages on the major browsers, where you can manage your cookie settings:Safari – https://support.apple.com/en-g...Google Chrome – https://support.google.com/chr...Microsoft Internet Explorer – https://support.microsoft.com/...Mozilla Firefox – https://support.mozilla.org/en...Advertising cookiesAs outlined above, you can manage third-party advertising cookies through the Interactive Advertising Bureau – https://www.iab.com/To the best of our knowledge, below is a list of our main advertising network partners, who set cookies on our websites to provide targeted adverts relevant to you and your interests:Facebook – https://www.facebook.com/polic...Google – https://support.google.com/ads...Twitter – https://twitter.com/en/privacyTo opt out of their cookies follow the links provided. Please note, this does not mean you will see fewer adverts; you will still see the same number, but they will be less targeted to your interests.HotjarWe use Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymised form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only) and preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymised user profile. Neither Hotjar nor Scottish Chamber Orchestra will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user.For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy at.: https://www.hotjar.com/legal/p...You can also opt out of Hotjar tracking at any time at: https://www.hotjar.com/legal/c...CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY NOTICEWe regularly review our privacy notice, and may make changes from time to time. Any changes made will be posted to this page, and will apply from the time we post them. This privacy statement was last updated on 21 September 2020. HOW TO CONTACT USIf you have any comments on our privacy notice, or information we hold about you please contact us by email or write to us at Scottish Chamber Orchestra, 4 Royal Terrace, Edinburgh EH7 5AB.Never miss a beatSign up to our newsletter to hear about concerts, collaborations and what we’re getting up to.Sign me up!
